Thank you, my friend.
谢谢 我的朋友
Pleasure. Take care.
客气 保重
You shouldn't watch scary movies so close to bedtime.
睡前不该看恐怖片
Kate? Jamie!
Kate? Jamie
Dad!
爸爸
You're defending him.
你担任他的辩护律师
You know as well as I do, for good or bad, everyone deserves a defence.
你我都知道 无论好坏 每个人都有获得辩护的权利
Mr Burton will not be in court.
Burton不能担任本案律师
As he's a witness, he cannot act for the Crown in any way.
作为证人 他不能以任何方式 代表检方工作
So he just has to watch.
那么他只能旁观了
Foyle had a storage unit. Someone took it on after him.
Foyle租过一间储藏间 之后有人接手了
If something's not turning up, look somewhere else.
如果一处没有发现 就换一个地方找找
And what did you make for dinner that night?
那天晚饭你做了什么
Spaghetti carbonara!
奶油意面
- I should've fought him harder. - What are you saying?
- 我要是更努力反抗就好了 - 你说什么
- I scratched his head. - With your hands?
- 我抓破了他的头 - 用手直接抓的?
- And then I hid. - You moved?!
- 然后躲起来了 - 你换过地方?
- "The forensic team just found DNA at the cottage."
法医在度假屋发现了DNA
Foyle's?
Foyle的?
"They want to meet."
他们想见见
In the trauma of finding your wife, you look up and see a man
目睹妻子倒在血泊中 你当时处于极大的痛苦及震惊中
whose absence from your life would be very useful indeed,
你抬起头 透过窗户 看到一个人 如果没有他 你的生活会很平静
but it wasn't that man, was it, Mr Burton?
但不是这个人 是吗 Burton先生?
You just wanted it to be.
只是你希望是他而已
Sync:FRS@Õº“¡¿≠ÕØ“•
-==http://www.1000fr.net==- 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
SThe Escape Artist S01E03
脱罪大师 第一季 第三集
www.1000fr.net presents
-=风软FRM字幕组=- 翻译: 怪怪豆 雨潇 没脑聪 米大宝 校对: mgydz 时间轴: 图伊拉童谣
Thanks
谢谢
- Morning! - Good morning, Doctor Lambert.
- 早上好 - 早上好 Lambert医生
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉 我来晚了
Remind me...
什么情况来着
- Low-count DNA. Kate Burton. - Oh, yeah.
- 少量DNA Kate Burton - 想起来了
They'll try and trip you on the low count. Keep your answers simple.??
他们会企图在少量这点事与你纠缠 回答要简洁有针对性
Thanks for the tip. I've only done this three or 400 times.
多谢提醒 我只出庭过三四百次呢
Did this analysis prove conclusively
分析结果是否能决定性地证明
that the DNA discovered in the cottage matches that of a particular individual?
在度假屋中发现的DNA与 某一特定人员的DNA相匹配?
It did.
是的
Whose DNA did the sample match?
样本与谁的DNA匹配?
We matched the sample to the DNA of Mr Liam Foyle.
我们发现样本与Liam Foyle先生的匹配
We are very stringent about our quality controls. We take our job extremely seriously.
我们的质量控制非常严格 重视每一项工作
That is very reassuring.
让人很放心
Were you responsible for analysing DNA samples in connection with Crown vs Foyle last year?
在去年检方对Foyle的案子中 您是否负责DNA分析?
I believe so.
我想是的
You believe so?
你想是的?
Yes, we were.
是的 是我们承接的
And in order to do that, samples of my client's DNA would've been sent to
为了进行分析 我的委托人的DNA
and processed by your lab, is that correct?
被送往您的实验室进行分析 是这样吗
- Well, yes, there's a - Thank you.
- 是的 有... - 谢谢
So my client's DNA, at that time,
所以在那时 我的委托人的DNA
would've been effectively distributed throughout that lab like dust through an old house?
实际上已经存在于实验室的各个角落 就像旧屋里的灰尘 是吗
- My Lord! - I take it this is leading somewhere?
- 法官大人 - 请尽快切入主题
I'm just arriving now, My Lord.
马上 法官大人
Dr Lambert, I have a sworn statement from your laboratory
Lambert医生 我有一份您实验室人员的证词
that confirms a deep clean was performed in all clean-room areas on the 12th of this month.
证实本月12日 所有无尘室区域 都进行了一次深层清洁
You brought the schedule forward. Why was that?
您把清洁日期提前了 这是为什么
Oh, come on!
哦 拜托
Mr Mayfield...
Mayfield先生
Dr Lambert, if you please...
Lambert医生 请回答
We conduct regular cleaning.
我们定期进行清洁
We recently decided to increase the number of cleans -
最近 我们决定增加清洁次数
Why was it brought forward
为什么那次提前了
??Your cleaning schedule is normally enacted on a regulated basis,
我注意到您的清洁安排是定期执行的
so something must've happened.
所以一定是发生了什么
It was necessary.
是必要措施
Are you or are you not in the process of an internal investigation
你是否因为实验室内部污染问题
into the viability of contaminants within the laboratory?
正在接受内部调查?
Please answer yes or no.
请回答是或否
But you can't answer...
但你不能...
Yes.
是
Are you concerned about your failure rate?
您是否担心自己的失败率?
Am I...? Everyone's concerned about their failure rate!
我?人人都担心自己的失败率
- It's an industry-wide concern! - Thank you.
- 这是业内普遍关心的问题 - 谢谢
My Lord, this is new information.
法官大人 这属于新信息
It should've been disclosed, certainly.
当然应该提前公开
What's clear beyond doubt is, this evidence is utterly compromised.
不容置疑的是 DNA证据已经完全污染了
You have to stop her.
你得阻止她
It's a wee bit late for that.
有点晚了
She's twisting the facts around to make them wrong.
她在扭曲是否黑白
Doing a good job of it, too.
而且干得很棒
If we don't have this DNA, then what do we have?
如果DNA证据不算数 我们还有什么
A problem.
有问题了
Spaghetti carbonara and an Arctic roll for afters.
奶油意面 甜品是雪糕蛋糕
Miss Morris, that's a matter for defence counsel.
Morris小姐 这是辩方律师的问题
All I want to ask you about is the search of your storage unit,
我问的是搜查您储藏间的问题
not the defence alibi, such as it is.
不是辩方的不在场证明 虽然也就这样了
- Please stick to the matter at hand. - My Lord!
- 请不要偏离问题 - 法官大人
Get on with it, Mr Mayfield.
继续 Mayfield先生
Miss Morris, you maintain a contract with this storage facility?
Morris小姐 你与这家储藏仓库有租赁合同?
I do, yes.
是的
And when these premises were searched by the police a few days ago,
警方前几天搜查这一地点时
a pair of size-12 boots was recovered from your unit,
在你的储藏间 发现一双46码的鞋
- isn't that right? - Yes, er, the other unit.
- 是这样吗 - 是的 另外一间
Are these your boots? They seem rather large for you!
这双鞋是你的吗 尺寸比你大很多
What other unit?
什么另外一间?
My Lord, this is new information!
法官大人 这是新信息
???Which was given to my learned friend yesterday.
所有新信息昨天都交予对方律师了
Chain of continuity, My Lord...
法官大人 证据连续性问题
Usher.
法警
The warrant was for Eileen Morris's possessions in the storage unit.
搜查令是搜查Eileen Morris 在储藏间的财产
They had no authority to search F38.
他们无权搜查F38号储藏间
- If... - Only F37.
- 如果... - 只有F37
The search of F38 was unlawful.
搜查F38是非法的
If defence had a problem with the evidence, they should've argued it at the appropriate time.
如果辩方对证据有疑问 应该在合适的时间提出
The issue has only just come to light.
这一问题刚刚才显露出来
Foyle's previous use of F37 connects him to it.
Foyle曾使用F37 所以F37与他有关
It falls within the chain of continuity.
属于连续性证据
F38 was entirely separate!
F38则毫不相关
Judge, obviously I ask you to exclude this evidence under Section 78.
法官大人 我请求您根据第78节 排除这一证据???
It was the unit next door! It...
只是隔壁的储藏间 它...
And should you request, I will no doubt accede.
如果你提出请求 毫无疑问 我会同意
Then, I respectfully submit, My Lord,
那么 法官大人 我提出
there is no case to answer.
本案无辩可答
- In the absence of any viable evidence - - There is compelling evidence!
- 缺少可行证据 - 这是有力证据
The eyewitness evidence of a broken man,
目击证人万念俱灰
alone and devastated in the dark...
在黑夜中 独自一人 几近崩溃
Having heard arguments from counsel as to the strength of the evidence at this stage of the trial,
在听取双方律师对本案 目前证据力度的辩论后
I have concluded the following...
我做出以下结论
There is insufficient evidence for the case to continue for your consideration.
本案目前证据不足 无法供你们参考
For that reason, on my direction, you will return a verdict of not guilty.
因此 根据我的指令 请做出无罪判决
On His Lordship's direction,
根据法官大人指令
do you find the defendant not guilty?
你们是否认为被告无罪?
Not guilty.
无罪
And is that the verdict of you all?
陪审团是否达成一致?
Yes.
是的
All rise.
全体起立
Mr Foyle, you may leave the dock.
Foyle先生 你可以离开被告席了
Congratulations.
恭喜
Oh, thanks.
谢谢
Margaret...
Margaret...
Thank you, my friend.
谢谢 我的朋友
Pleasure. Take care.
客气 保重
Are you all right there, mate?
你还好吧 伙计
Sorry, my foot slipped.
抱歉 我脚滑了
Are you all right? Yeah?
你没事吧
Jamie...
Jamie...
Ah, she blows! Pull!
她来了 开瓶
A consummate performance.
完美的辩护
First class.
堪称一流
This is for you.
这是给你的
I believe you've earned it.
你用行动赢来的
Pretty juicy, too!
也很美
Ooh! Thank you.
哇 谢谢
Vadim!
Vadim
Excuse me.
失陪
Mr Will.
Will先生
You're looking well.
你气色不错
I'm sorry to hear about your wife.
你妻子的事很遗憾
- Thank you. - If there is anything I can do for you...
- 谢谢 - 要是有什么需要我帮忙的...
What time do you finish work?
你什么时候下班
I clone it fast.
我复制得很快
The name you wanted - Beinn Alligin.
你要的名字 Beinn Alligin
Hi.
嗨
Look, sorry, I just wanted to come and...
抱歉 我只是想来...
I'm not sure why I came, actually.
其实我也不知道为什么要来
Was that who I think it was?
他是那个谁吗
I thought you'd be out celebrating.
还以为你去庆祝了
No, just...
没有 那个...
I'm sorry.
对不起
- It's just... - Your job.
- 那个... - 那是你的工作
Look, no hard feelings.
别往心里去
- By which I mean - - Watch yourself, Maggie.
- 我的意思是... - 自己小心 Maggie
Can I...
我能...
Can I come round tonight, please?
我今晚能过来吗 拜托
I'm freaking out!
我好害怕
"I think this is most inappropriate."
这样很不合适
Oh, come on, think...!
拜托 你想想
How did he know? There's no way he could've known!
他怎么会知道 他不可能知道
"If you're that concerned, I suggest you call the police."
要是这么担心 我建议你报警
Oh, God!
老天
Oh, God, I've just completely...
天 我彻底...
We have a window for appeal.
我们还有时间上诉
- Ohh!Come on! - Maybe not now, but...
- 不一定马上 但... - 拜托
- No, optimism was never... - Forget it. We lost.
- 不 乐观精神永不... - 算了吧 我们输了
It's over.
结束了
Will!
Will
Are you coming?
你来吗
I never knew about this place.
我不知道有这么个地方
Yeah, Kate's cousin lets us use it every now and again.
嗯 Kate的表兄让我们偶尔来住
Cracking bottle of wine inside, if you're interested?
进屋开瓶酒 有兴趣吗
??It took some real sleuthing to find you.
我费了九牛二虎之力才找到你
You know my methods, Watson.
你了解我的路数 Watson
Red or white?
红酒还是白酒?
Er... You chose.
你决定吧
Huhh! How are you, Danny?!
你好吗 Danny
All the better for seeing you, mate!
很高兴见到你 小子
Pop those in the pot, would you?
把这些扔锅里 好吗
That's alive, alive-O.
这是活的 活蹦乱跳的
Now you're talking.
你真麻烦
Ah, here! You pasta, me sauce.
给 你煮意粉 我煮酱汁
Don't you need a permit for those?
这东西不需要许可证吗
Public right to fish in tidal waters - Malcomson v O'Dea, 1863,
有潮水域钓鱼公权 Malcomson v O'Dea 1863年
before that, the Magna Carta.
在那之前 大宪章
To be fair, it's not mentioned at all in the Magna Carta,
公平地说 大宪章里根本没提及
everyone just thinks it was.
大家都想当然以为有
So strictly speaking, right now, we just broke the law.
所以严格来说 我们现在已经触犯法律了
- Well, to be precise, you did! - Except now, you're an accessory.
- 说清楚点 是你违法了 - 可惜你已经是从犯了
What about me?
那我呢
Probably just a caution.
可能只会受到警告
- Thanks! - You're very welcome!
- 谢谢 - 不客气
Stop crying and pour some wine.
别吵吵了 倒酒吧
Not even a civil suit!
连民事诉讼都不提
We're not going in that direction.
我不打算那样做
Even if we get him, no-one wins.
就算胜了官司 也没有赢家
It's not going to bring her back.
她也不会复生
So, we're just going to sit here, then?
那我们就干坐着?
Are you keeping busy?
最近忙吗
I've been offered Chambers Manager at Citadel.
Citadel邀请我去做律所经理
Manchester.
在曼彻斯特
You do know what they do to QPR supporters there, don't you?!
你知道那儿的人是怎么对付 女王公园巡游者队球迷的吧
I'm sorry you had to take that fall, Danny.
很抱歉当时麻烦你了 Danny
You had us all worried for a minute,
我们那阵子都很担心你
disappearing like that.
突然就消失了
Why's that?
怎么会
You always seem so planned.
你一向有条不紊
You haven't seen the school run.
你没见过我送儿子上学
I mean, it's not like you to do anything on the fly.
我是说 你不像是仓促行事的人
Well, that's me all over, Danny.
我就是那样的 Danny
I'm just full of surprises.
浑身惊喜
How long does it take to get to Edinburgh?
多久能到爱丁堡
Ten minutes, the way you drive.
10分钟 以你开车的速度
Try not to take off, OK.
尽量别开太快 好吗
I'll be back as soon as I can.
我尽快回来
Look after Granny for me.
替我照顾奶奶
Dad...
爸爸
Yeah?
嗯?
You're shaking.
你在发抖
Look, I mean, if you really were thinking of coming here,
如果你真心考虑来这儿
we'd, obviously, be very interested in having you join the set.
我们当然很有兴趣让你加入
No, I'm actively looking. My family needs a change of scene so...
不 我还在找 我家需要换换环境...
Oh, well, for families, it's a lovely place!
对一家人来说 这是个好地方
You should rent a car and drive around a bit while you're here,
趁还在这里 你该租辆车四处转转
see the scenery.
看看景色
I might just do that.
值得考虑
What would you like?
要点什么
Hi. Do you mind if I use your loo?
嗨 能借下厕所吗
Thanks.
谢了
What's the law on home invasion these days? I'm a little cloudy.
现在擅闯民居要判几年? 我不太清楚
What's a proportionate response to someone surprised in their home by a stranger?
在自己家惊遇陌生人应该作何反应
I need to ask you something.
我有事要问你
I'm on Facebook.
我有Facebook
I know.
我知道
Well,
那个
you're here now,
既然来了
so you can ask me whatever you like.
想问什么就问吧
When did you decide to kill my wife?
你是什么时候决定杀我妻子的?
Please, I need to know.
拜托 我必须知道
When you killed her,
你杀她时
did she die quickly?
她马上就死了吗
Are you playing a character?
你在扮上帝吗
Are you?
是不是
Are you all the way up there, looking all the way down here?
你是高高在上地俯视我吗
And do you think I'm a little bit stupid?
你觉得我有一点点蠢吗
You're going about this all wrong.
你这事完全没做对
Well, you're the expert.
你是专家
"When did you decide to kill my wife?"
"你是什么时候决定杀我妻子的?"
You and your brain!
你这脑子啊
Have you ever seen a brain up close?
你细看过大脑吗
It looks like a cauliflower.
很像菜花
The neural cortex looks like icing.
神经皮质就像糖衣
They say it's what separates us from the animals.
据说那是我们区别于动物的地方
But we are animals. We're mammals. Like a lion.
但我们就是动物 哺乳动物 和狮子一样
You wouldn't blame a lion for being a lion, would you, Will?
你不会怪狮子显本性吧 Will
Especially if you were the one who let him out.
尤其是放他出来的人是你
How do you live with yourself?
你怎么能容忍自己
I forgive myself.
我原谅自己
You're very clever!
你很聪明
My pen...
注射器
Get the pen!
去拿注射器
Ambulance.
救护车
- "It's an oval tube." - Oval tube! Yes! Yes!
- 是个椭圆管 - 椭圆管 找到了
- It's sort of grey with an orange end. - "That's it."
- 是灰色的 一头是橙色的 - 就是那个
I'm putting you on speaker.
我要开免提了
Can you still hear me?
还能听见吗
- "Yes.??Are you holding the tube?" - Yeah.
- 能听见 你拿着针管吗 - 是的
- "Now put your fist around the tube." - OK.
- 现在握着针管 - 好
"Hold the orange tip near the thigh."
将橙色那头靠近大腿
He has his trousers on!
他穿着裤子
"The needle will go through.??
针头会穿透它
"Hold the orange tip near his thigh,
将橙色那头靠近大腿
"with your other hand, pull off the blue safety release."
用另一只手拿掉蓝色安全扣
- Done it - "Now, swing and firmly push the tip against the thigh until it clicks.
- 拿掉了 - 现在 迅速用力扎进大腿 听到喀哒声后
"Hold it there for ten seconds. Did you get that?"
握着不动 等10秒钟 听明白了吗
Swing, click, wait. OK. Here goes.
扎 响 等 好 我来了
What was that?
什么声
"You probably heard the needle mechanism. It's spring-loaded."
你听到的可能是针管的机械装置 它用的是弹簧
- OK. - "The drug in the EpiPen should keep him steady till the ambulance gets to you.
- 好 - 注射器里的肾上腺素应该能稳住他 等救护车来
-Are you still with me? -Yeah. I'm here.
- 你还在吗 - 嗯 我在
"You're doing great."
你做得很棒
What now?
然后呢
OK, you can take it out.
好 可以拔出来了
"Look at the barrel. Is there a red strip visible on the barrel?
看看针筒 上面是否有条红道
"That will tell you that the drug went in.
有就说明药物注射进去了
r, hang on.
稍等
I can't see it!
没看到
"Just above the writing, there's a window."
就在标签上面 有个小口
Oh, yes! Yes, yes, yes, it's there!
有有有 找到了
"Is the patient responding?"
病人有反应了吗
"Sir? Sir? Hello?
先生 先生 喂
"Anybody hear me?
有人吗
"Hello?
喂
"Anybody there?
有人在吗
"Hello, sir?
喂 先生
"Can you hear me?"
能听见吗
- Are you all right? - Yeah, just a bit of smoke.
- 你还好吗 - 嗯 就吸了点烟
- Just the two of you up there? - Yeah.
- 就你们两个? - 嗯
Showing vasodilation. Capillary leak.
血管扩张 毛细血管渗漏
Is he going to be OK? Bad shoulder bleed here.
- 他不会有事吧 - 肩头在流血
Let's concentrate on his breathing. Here we go.
先搞定呼吸问题 来
You're going to be all right. We're the paramedics.
你会好起来的 我们是救护员
You'd better come with us.
你最好跟我们走
No, my car's -
不 我的车...
No, mate, we can't leave you.
不 兄弟 我们不能让你留下
You're going to come with us.
你要跟我们走
Bring that green bag, please.
把那个绿包拿过来 谢谢
One, two, three, lift!
一 二 三 抬
OK, let's go. Let's go.
好 走吧 走吧
Lucky your friend was there. He used your EpiPen.
幸亏你朋友在 他给你注射了肾上腺素
We've got some more adrenalin ready.???
如果需要 我们这里还有 好吗
Everything is OK.
没事了
I know your breathing's not that easy,
我知道你呼吸不太顺畅
but we'll be in the hospital in five minutes.
我们5分钟就能到医院
??Hang on there. Just open your eyes.
好吗 坚持住 睁开眼睛
Chest compressions!
胸外按压
OK, we've got one milligram of adrenalin.
好 注射1毫克肾上腺素
OK, well done. All right, mate...
好的 很好 兄弟...
Mind if I open a window? I think I'm going to be sick.
开下窗行吗 我有点恶心
He's arrested in the back!
心脏停跳了
Arrested!
心脏停跳
William Burton?
William Burton?
Will you come with me, please?
跟我来一下好吗
Did you and Mr Foyle have any interactions?
你和Foyle先生之间有事发生吗
Yes.
是的
He attacked me and I stabbed him.
他打我 我捅了他
With this...
用的这个
Quite a shock, don't you think?
很惊人 你不觉得吗
What is?
什么
He's dead?
他死了?
Keep reading.
继续看
Excuse me.
请问
Erm, does Vadim Kumarin still work here?
Vadim Kumarin还在这儿做吗
Do you know where he might be? Do you know...
你知道他可能去哪儿吗 你知道...
OK.
好吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Welcome to Scotland.
欢迎来苏格兰
Oh, is that where I am?!
原来我是在这儿
I wondered why everyone was Scottish.
怪不得都是苏格兰人
Some good news from the Fiscal.
检察官那儿有好消息
They'd recommend acceptance if you offered a Section 76 plea of culpable homicide.
如果你按照第76节的过失杀人来申辩 他们将愿意接受
Probably a 30 percent discount on sentence.
也许能免去百分之三十的刑罚
That's nine years at most. Out in six.
最多判九年 六年就能出狱
And that's good news because...?
为什么这也算好消息
Because you're in serious trouble.
因为你的处境很不乐观
If you're thinking of going not guilty, that's a murder trial!
你想按照无罪来辩护吗 这是在审理谋杀案啊
The Crown's going to be all out for your blood.
检方非置你于死地不可
Look, I typed up a draft plea offer for you.
我帮你拟了一份申辩书
This is a choice.
这也不失为一种选择
You've got life, with a minimum of 20 years for murder,
你接下来要么谋杀罪成立至少服刑20年
or sign the offer, do six years and see your son finish school,
要么签了申辩书 服刑六年还能看着你儿子毕业
instead of missing the whole thing.
总好过错过一切
I'm not missing a single second!
我一秒都不会错过
Don't be like this. Come on.
别这样 拜托
You need to seriously consider this.
你真的需要好好考虑
- Do you think I did it? - No!
- 你觉得人是我杀的吗 - 不
No.
不
Of course I don't.
我当然不这么想
Make sure you recycle that.
记得把这个拿走
I appreciate you coming down, Jen, but I think I'll do it myself.
我感激你能来 Jen 但我还是自己来好了
You can't.
你不能这样
I can. In fact, I can do all of it myself.
我能 事实上我可以全靠自己
No, you can't!
不 你不能
This is Scots law, idiot.
苏格兰法律有规定 白痴
- There's a thousand differences. - Renton Brown, right?
- 有很大的不同 - Renton&Brown刑事诉讼法对吧
That's a punchy read.
这还不简单
You've always been there for me, and I'm sorry,
你总是为我着想 对不起
but this isn't going to work out.
但这个方法行不通
What do you think you are doing? Eh?
你觉得你这是在干什么
- I'm trying to help you here! - I know.
- 我是想帮你 - 我知道
Thank you,
谢谢
but I'll take it from here.
但让我来吧
Court!
开庭
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们
the charge on the indictment is that, on the 23rd of March,
起诉的指控为 于三月二十三日
at a house near Kielder Forest in Scotland,
位于苏格兰Kielder森林 附近的一处房屋里
William Burton did assault Liam Michael Foyle
William Burton袭击了Liam Michael Foyle
and did stab on the body with a knife containing thereon a substance,
并用刀刺伤了他 刀上含有一种物质
knowing that this would cause severe injury, anaphylaxis
他知道这能对其接受者 造成严重创伤 过敏反应
and death to the recipient,
并导致死亡
and he did murder him.
是他谋杀了他
Call the diet of Her Majesty's advocate against William Burton.
检方决定起诉William Burton
We have no opening speeches in Scottish courts, Mr Burton,
苏格兰法庭没有开庭陈诉 Burton先生
just in case you were planning on making one at this stage.
提醒一下以免你准备要说
Oh. Really?
是这样吗
Mr Burton, you know you have been strongly advised against representing yourself.
Burton先生 有人强烈反对过你自辩
It's been made very clear, My Lord.
说得很清楚了 法官大人
Very well.
很好
Er, can I move my papers to the table?
我能把材料拿到桌子上吗
No.
不行
I can't very well run my case from the dock, can I?
我在被告席上不大好辩护吧
That, Mr Burton, is exactly what you are going to do.
Burton先生 这正是你要做的
What are you doing?
你在干什么
- Is this a common allergy? - Not really.
- 这是常见的过敏症吗 - 并不是
It's an allergy to a particular gastropod. Specifically, limpets.
是对某种腹足动物过敏 具体来说就是 帽贝
He was deathly allergic to limpets?
帽贝能对他产生致命的过敏吗
More specifically, an active protein known as tropomyosin.
更准确的说 是一种叫做 原肌蛋白球的活性蛋白引起的
And where was this allergen?
那么过敏原在哪
How did Mr Foyle come into contact with it?
Foyle先生是如何接触到它的
Localised swelling at the wound site
伤口位置局部肿胀表明
suggest it may have been present on the weapon used to injure him before he died.
可能是来自于死前伤害他的凶器
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你 医生
Mr Burton?
Burton先生
No, thank you, My Lord.
没有要说的 谢谢你 法官大人
Mr Burton, you are aware, of course,
Burton先生 你一定清楚
that once you give evidence on your own behalf,
一旦你为自己提供证据
you are opening yourself up to cross-examination by the Crown?
你将受到检察官的交叉询问对吗
Very well aware, My Lord.
我很清楚 法官大人
- "What now?" - "OK, you can take it out.
- "现在该干什么" - "好 可以拔出来了"
"Look at the barrel. Is there a red strip visible on the barrel?
"看看针筒 上面是否有条红道"
"That will tell you that the drug went in."
"有就说明药物注射进去了"
"Er, hang on. Hang on.
"稍等 稍等"
"I can't see it!"
"我没看到"
"Just above the writing, there's a window."
"就在标签上面 有个小口"
"Oh, yes! Yes, yes, yes, it's there!"
"有有有 找到了"
"Is the patient responding?"
"病人有反应了吗"
"Sir? Sir? Hello? Anybody hear me?"
"先生 先生 喂 有人吗"
You appear to be very calm during this interaction.
你在这个过程中表现得很镇静
- Were you? -I was trying to be.
- 对吗 - 我有努力这么做
What were you doing in Kielder Forest, Mr Burton?
你去Kielder森林干什么 Burton先生
I had a job interview in Carlisle.
我到Carlisle参加工作面试
The person I spoke to suggested I tour around a bit.
接待我的人建议我四处逛逛
Do you normally conduct job interviews with a knife?
你一般参加面试都会带刀吗
I got married with a knife.
我刀不离身
Every Scotsman worth his kilt gets married with a knife.
穿苏格兰裙的就会随身带刀
You bumped into Mr Foyle by pure chance?
你遇见Foyle先生只是偶然吗
Yes. I saw him in a pub and I felt compelled to confront him.
是的 我在一家酒吧撞见他 觉得有必要质问他
You sought him out to force a confession.
你去找他 强迫他招供
Isn't that correct?
是这样吗
Yes.
是的
Yes?
是吗
Yes, that's right.
是的 没错
Double jeopardy law, pertaining to new evidence.
一罪不两罚 即便有新证据
I believe Mr Burton has answered the question.
我想Burton已经回答了问题
My Lord.
法官大人
A confession -
招供
something that you would've desired very much.
是你十分想要得到的
Yes.
是的
And yet when he denied you this request,
然而他拒绝了你这个请求
you took his life.
你就杀了他
- No. - You flew into a rage and attacked him with a knife, didn't you?
- 没有 - 你怒不可遏然后袭击了他 对吗
When was this, sorry?
是说什么时候来着
When you slashed him with the knife,
你用刀割伤他的时候
as you've said clearly in your statement!
正如你在供词中所说
Oh, yes, before I carried him out of a burning building.
正是 在我把他背出着火的房子之前
Mr Burton!
Burton先生
Just being clear on chronology.
我只是想说明先后顺序
Flying close to the sun.
别太过火
A gastropod allergy,
腹足动物过敏
a specific kind of shellfish -
还是特别针对其中的帽贝
not exactly easy information to find out.
这样的信息可不容易找到
No, I'd imagine not.
是的 我想不容易
Have you ever had cause to access a client's medical records?
你是否曾经看过委托人的医疗记录
Yes, though only if pertinent to the case.
是的 但仅限于与案件有关的情况下
In the case of Sandra Mullins,
在Sandra Mullins一案中
you were lead counsel for Mr Foyle's defence
你是Foyle先生的首席辩护律师
I was.
是的
Did you ever request any medical information regarding Mr Foyle?
你是否索取过任何 Foyle先生的医疗信息
- No. - You did not?
- 没有 - 没有吗
No, I did not access his files.
不 我没有看过他的病历
I believe his "no" was sufficient.
我想他已经明确的表达了否定
My Lord. You cannot prove this, of course.
法官大人 显然你无法证明这点
He was your client.
他是你的委托人
You were intimately acquainted with his information.
你十分熟悉他的信息
No. Erm...
不
Confidential medical files are all digitised and kept securely at the solicitors,
保密的医疗档案全都 电子归档由事务律师保管
or, presumably, equally securely at his doctors or hospital.
也可能由他的医生或医院保管
Which is a long-winded way of saying no, I did not access his files,
绕这个弯子是想说明我没看过他的病历
and, yes, I can prove it.
并且我可以证明这点
What Mr Burton is asking of you is very simple, ladies and gentlemen.
Burton先生对你们的要求很简单 女士们先生们
He wants you to believe his little story.
他想让你们相信他编出来的故事
He wants you to believe that, through an ironic twist of fate,
他想让你们相信 这叫造化弄人
this was the wrong knife,
这把错误的刀
in the wrong hand, at the wrong time.
在错误的时间 拿在了错误的人手中
I respectfully submit to you that this is pure fabrication.
我敬请各位看清这纯粹是凭空捏造
This was foreknowledge, with malicious intent.
这是恶意的早有预谋
He will tell you otherwise, but I ask only this question -
他自然另有一套说辞 但我只有一个问题
he tells a good story,
他编的故事很完美
but do we really believe him?
但我们真的就这么相信他吗
I'm a lawyer.
我是一个律师
I have lived and believed in the law all my life.
我一生都奉行并且坚信法律
But until the law happens to you,
但等到法律问题落到自己头上
believe me, you don't know which way you're going to go.
相信我 你会不知所措
is the man I know, beyond all doubt, murdered my wife.
就是谋杀我妻子的凶手
I could've done a lot of things to him.
我本可以为所欲为
Instead,
但没有
I saw him suffer and I called an ambulance.
我发现他很痛苦 于是叫了救护车
I removed him from danger.
我帮助他脱离危险
I did what any decent human being should do.
我的所作所为 是一个人该做的
But make no mistake,
但毫无疑问
I did those things out of nothing more than a sincere duty to our common decency.
我这么做 只是出于做人的良知
I did so because that's what's expected when you're a person in the world.
我这么做 只因为社会规则要求我这么做
I risked my life to save the man who took away my heart...
我冒着生命危险救的男人 他夺走了我心爱的人
..my compass,
我前行的灯塔
my anchor,
停泊的港湾
my best friend.
我的挚友
I faced him down with a knife in my hand, I could've let him burn!
我手握着刀 看他倒在地上 本可以让他去
In the circumstances,
在这种情况下
I believe I exerted an extraordinary amount of restraint.
我已经表现出了极大的克制
Liam Foyle is dead.
Liam Foyle死了
I rejoice in his passing.
这让我非常高兴
But you should not convict me of his murder.
但你不应为此指控我杀人
- Will! - That's your one.
- Will! - 你的
Will.
Will
Oh, hi!
哦 嗨
OK, interesting...
你怎么来了
I wanted to talk to you.
我想跟你聊聊
I'd hurry up if I were you, you know what juries can be like.
那抓紧吧 你知道陪审团的作风
They can't deliberate forever.
他们总会讨论出个结果的
How are you feeling?
你感觉如何
- How am I feeling? - When you heard what happened.
- 我感觉如何 - 就是当你听说这事的时候
Come on, you weren't just a wee bit relieved?
难道没有松了口气吗
I need to talk to you.
我想和你聊一下
Moral support?
需要精神支持吗
Legal advice.
是法律建议
I've been grappling with a case that's been bothering me,
我最近有个案子挺棘手
and wondered if you could help.
想问你是否能帮忙
Be right back.
马上回来
Shoot.
说吧
Something occurred to me the other day...
某天我突然想起来
If you wanted to break into a safe,
如果想撬开保险箱
the first person you'd call is a locksmith, and, um,
首先应该找锁匠
if you wanted to commit murder and get away with it,
那如果想犯罪了之后再脱罪
you might just want to talk to a criminal barrister.
也许就该和刑事律师谈谈
That's an interesting idea.
有趣的想法
I see enough cases turn on discovery to know that a perfect crime only stays perfect
我见过很多案子 发觉想要毫无破绽
if it's done in plain sight, wouldn't you say?
只有让事发情节一目了然 你觉得呢?
Could be.
也许吧
Everyone would have all the facts and still have no idea how he really did it.
每个人都清楚案发情况 但谁也不知道他到底是怎么做的
Step one - he'd find the Achilles heel.
第一步 发现要害之处
A deathly allergy, say. A rare one.
比如致命的过敏症 很少见
How did this person find out something like that?
这人怎么可能发现呢
What does a criminal barrister do all day long?
刑事律师每天最常干的是什么
- Chase invoices. - Talk to criminals.
- 追讨发票 - 和罪犯聊天
Wouldn't that give him an address book, full of potential contacts?
他想问什么 就能问出什么
For example, on the case that I'm working on,
拿我手上的案子举例
the man was seen talking to a known criminal.
当事人被发现曾和一名罪犯交谈
How would the person be sure it was him?
怎么认出是他呢
The criminal, I mean.
我是说那个罪犯
Presuming it was a he, of course...
假设就是他吧
He was well-known to the eyewitness.
当然证人很熟悉他
Yeah, but was it day or night? Was he on foot, in a vehicle?
没错 但是白天还是晚上 他是走路还是开车呢
Was the observer under any stress at all?
目击者当时承受的压力大吗
Step two -
第二步
what if he found a natural-occurring source for the allergen, somewhere innocent and every day?
找到一个获得致敏原的途径 每日常见并且不引起怀疑
If they argue self-defence, they might load up a weapon with that allergen to administer the dose.
如果从自我防卫来辩论 他们可以全力拿致敏物剂量说事
I'm with you so far.
我同意
But to put so much weight on one dose of allergen might not be enough, don't you think?
但只在致敏剂量上下大力气 似乎还不够 你觉得呢
I wouldn't know the first thing about it.
我不知道
Step three -
第三步
these people with allergies of such severity that they cause anaphylaxis,
过敏反应如此严重的人
they carry these little life-saving pens with them, don't they, called EpiPens?
都会随身携带急救针 叫做肾上腺素
Do you think it might be possible to repurpose a pen as a poison pen?
有没有可能 急救针被掉包了
By replacing the carrier solution with a solution of allergen,
被换成了含有过敏原的药物
a person might sabotage the very thing that would save a person's life.
救命的药物被人为地破坏了
- That sounds diabolical. - It does, doesn't it?
- 听起来太可怕了 - 没错啊
You mentioned a legal question.
你说有什么法律问题
And if that person called 999,
如果这个人打了急救电话
and they talked them through administering that pen to the victim,
他们让他给受害人打急救针
it's almost collusion in the crime.
这几乎就是合谋犯罪
They'd be walking that person, step by step, through the murder.
他们一步步参与了杀人的整个过程
Oh, you mean they'd have a public record of the conversation.
哦你是说公开的电话记录
- Yes. - Ah, that might fly.
- 是的 - 那太不可能了
But I really don't think anyone would seriously attempt it.
我觉得不会有人真那么干的
- Why not? - I think murder's against the law!
- 为什么 - 因为杀人违法啊
I mean, last time I looked...
就我所知...
- Will... - You're drawing a line. A big red one.
- Will... - 你在玩火 很危险
There's a huge difference between knowing where that line is and stepping over it.
知道法律界限在哪儿 和真正突破界限 有巨大的差别
I know I couldn't.
我不会这么做的
Why not?
为什么
I'd be scared of getting caught.
我怕被抓住
You just said it was the perfect crime.
你说了这是完美犯罪
Oh, it is!
哦没错
It is.
没错
Except for three things...
但有三个破绽
Three?
三个?
Really?
真的吗
One -
第一
disposing the weapon.
处理凶器
There'd be two EpiPens, the innocent one and the murder weapon.
有两支肾上腺素 一支正常一支有毒
The killer would have to discharge the innocent EpiPen at the locus
凶手在凶案现场就用掉了那支正常的
so it looked like he'd done what he talked to the emergency services about.
和他告诉急救中心的一样
Then I imagine he'd have to chuck the poisoned EpiPen into the sharps disposal bags ??
然后他会把有毒的那支放进专用垃圾盒
But there's a chance it could be found before being incinerated if the police do a search.
但在烧成灰烬前 警察也许就搜出来了
Ah! Very clever.
啊 很聪明
Two - obtaining the pen in the first place.
第二 一开始弄得到针剂
He'd have to know someone with a... with a prescription already.
他得认识能开到这类处方的人
Hm... Good point.
嗯 有道理
Oh, and then there's number three...
然后 就是第三点
"Patient suffered IgE phylum Mollusca allergy,
"病人因对软体动物过敏"
"severe bronchospasm and anaphylaxis and..."
"导致严重支气管痉挛反应"
under 'Additional Observations', hidden away in the footnotes,
在补充意见一栏的脚注中
"..some local swelling at wound...
"伤口和注射部位"
"..and injection site".
"有局部肿胀"
But, you know, they don't test for epinephrine after death,
但他们不会在人死后测试肾上腺素含量
so there's no way of knowing if the EpiPen had been used or not,
所以肾上腺素针到底有没有打 没人知道
except for the puncture wound.
除非是检测伤口
So my number three is this -
所以第三点就是
risk of a follow-up histology on local puncture site.
对伤口进行后续组织样本检测
You have a very creative mind.
你的想法很有创意
But would that person be able to sleep soundly,
那个人能每晚安睡吗
knowing that at any moment, there might be another post-mortem that identified allergen at the EpiPen site?
他不知道什么时候会又有场尸检 检测肾上腺素中的致敏原
Well, I guess that depends...
我想这要看了
On what?
看什么
On whether the body's been cremated...
看尸体是否被火化了
Can the foreman stand, please?
请陪审团团长起立
- Have you reached a verdict? - We have.
- 已有判决了吗 - 已有了
In the case of Her Majesty's Advocate against William Burton,
针对William Burton的公诉
how do you find the accused on the charge of murder?
对当事人犯谋杀罪名的指控如何判定
Not proven.
证据不足
Yes!
太好了
Silence, please!
请安静
Mr Burton! Mr Burton! Any comments, Mr Burton?
Burton先生 Burton先生 有什么要说的吗
Not proven, of course, the third verdict available in Scottish law.
证据不足 三审判决即时生效
Effectively an acquittal,
无罪当庭释放
but one which suggests a suspicion of guilt...
但有人认为这次可疑的...
Do you think you would've got away with it in an English court of law? Mr Burton!
你之前想过会无罪释放吗 Burton先生
Take care.
保重
OK...
好了
..hold it down.
下来点
Join our FRS/FRM and have fun! QQ Group No. 77207643/frzhaopin2@gmail.com
时间轴招聘群号：77207643 翻译组招聘邮箱：frzhaopin2@gmail.com 与最新美剧亲密接触 享受海量FTP下载
welcome to www.1000fr.net
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.net==- 欢迎加入